# Abhishek Kumar

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

RZ B-33 Dabri Extension Delhi, National Capital Territory of Delhi, 110045 abhi.abik@gmail.com +91-8860965877

#### **SUMMARY**

Energetic Software Engineer with 2 years of experience developing RESTful APIs for the web as well as mobile services. Skills include creative problem-solving, quick to learnability and intermediate programming skills. Able to communicate effectively with a team and very keen to develop more professional skills.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## YAS Techno Companion

Gurugram, Haryana January 2019 - Present

## **Software Engineer**

- Progressively Participated in the development phases of the application.
- Maintaining the Live applications and serving the maintenance and support for the same.
- Actively Participated in the pre-development planning for the new applications.

## Appster LLP

Gurugram, Haryana January 2018 - December 2018

## **Associate Software Engineer**

- Became a core member of the project development team.
- Designed and worked on the backend code structure to provide the RESTful APIs and integrating the same with the
- Managed backend support of a Live Application and also served client's changes to the product with live users.
- Designed a Web Admin Portal of a mobile Application both the frontend and backend of the portal.

## Appster LLP

July 2017 - January 2018

Gurugram, Haryana

**Trainee Software Engineer** 

- Received the industrial level training as a backend PHP developer.
- Introduced and learned Laravel framework.
- Got familiar with basics of Web/App development.
- Learned basic understanding of RESTful APIs, MySql, HTML, CSS, Ajax, Javascript, and other useful technologies.
- Served as helping hands to senior developers in various projects.
- Learned and experienced the Software development model.
- Learned Software Development management tools like JIRA.

## **EDUCATION**

## Institute of Informatics and Communication, University of Delhi

New Delhi, Delhi Graduated July 2017

Master's Degree

M.Sc in Informatics(CGPA - 7.23)

## S.G.T.B. Khalsa College, University of Delhi Bachelor's Degree

New Delhi, Delhi Graduated July 2014

B.Sc(Hons.) in Electronics (Percentage - 64.4%)

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Coding Competent Database Knowledge Competent PHP Intermediate Laravel Intermediate MySql Competent HTML/CSS/JS Competent Agile Methodology Intermediate VCS (Git) Competent Debugging Intermediate Critical Thinking Competent Communication Advanced Team Collaboration Advanced

#### **PROJECTS**

## LASHD (At Appster & YAS Techno Companion)

A mobile application which provides beauty services on a click.

Creatives can add their profile and add services they offer, and a customer can book any service and pick any creative they want.

Playstore Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.lashd.lashdapp

App Store Link: https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/lashd/id1393913221?mt=8

My Role & Responsibilities

- Designing the Restful API for all the functionalities of the application with the minimum response time by using Queues/Jobs.
- Worked on the Stripe Payment Gateway with the functionalities of Adding a new customer, Saving the card, Pre-Auth, capturing and refund of payments.
- Maintaining and Deployment of the code on the different server instances for QA check and the live environment too
  using version control.
- Used MySql as the relational database to store and use the user's data.
- Developed an Admin Panel for the application to manage all the services and users.
- Experience of handling the live application and to perform development changes.
- Managed to automate some processes in the application like sending emails and notifications at different events.
- Technology Stack: Php, HTML, ajax, javascript, JSON, Mysql, Laravel

#### Hauler (At Appster)

 $\label{lem:continuous} A \, mobile \, application \, where \, truck \, drivers \, can \, find \, any \, jobs \, posted \, \, by \, \, the \, customer \, via \, a \, web \, \, portal.$ 

Play store Link:https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hauler

App Store Link: https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/hauler/id1209364226?mt=8

My Role & Responsibilities

- Fixed and creation of Restful APIs to ease the user's experience.
- Worked with Google Map API to get an estimated route and time between two coordinates.
- Worked on Datatables for Admin Panel of the application.
- Maintaining code using version control.
- Technology Stack:Php, Html, Ajax, Datatables, Mysql, JSON, Laravel

## **ACTIVITIES & HOBBIES**

## Placement Coordinator

Volunteered as a placement coordinator in post-graduation with the responsibilities of inviting and coordinating with the companies and organizing the placement drive for the batch. Learned a lot about professional communication skills and managing the people.

## **Event Organiser**

Volunteered as an event organizer for the institute's technical festival with the responsibilities of organizing different events and inviting and making students participate in the same from different institutes.

## **Hobbies**

Reading, Writing, Cooking & Gymming